In this clip, we're going to talk about the proper way to remove and replace worn front brake hoses on a nineteen ninety-one Ford Explorer.
In this step, we're going to talk about types of brake fluid and the proper way to fill your vehicles master cylinder.
What you're looking at here, this is DOT-3.
That's Department of Transportation spec level 3.
They also have four and five, you're going to want to refer to your vehicles owner's manual for the particular fluid recommended by the manufacturer.
DOT-3 is the most common and it is recommended by Ford for the ninety-one Explorer.
This is your vehicles master cylinder.
It will have a level on it for minimum and maximum fills.
You can see this line right here, it says max.
That's as full as they want it.
If you're done bleeding the brakes, the fluid level in a master cylinder is going to be relatively depleted.
Which, will sink the sensor and turn on your red brake light.
You want to make sure to top off your master cylinder after you bleed your brakes.
Go ahead and take and fill it up.
It is possible for these floats to get stuck.
So, you're going to want to keep an eye on it and make sure that it comes up to the appropriate level.
If it's not moving, tap the side of it and your float will come up for you.
As you can see, the float came up right there.
That is the level sensor.
Can you see that?
See how it comes up?
That triggers the system, it will turn the red brake light on if your fluid level is low.
Right there, is plenty of fluid.
Let me go ahead and take and put my master cylinder cap back on.
That is the different types of brake fluid and the proper way to fill your master cylinder.